我们来讨论人类视觉系统。现在我不是生物学家，所以我要付出代价
Let’s discuss the human vision system. Now I am not a biologist, so I am going to give
你是工程师对人类视觉系统如何运作的印象。
you an engineer’s impression of how the human vision system works.
首先，我们拥有自己的眼睛，并且看着眼睛也许是最明显的特征
Firstly we have the eye itself, and looking at an eye perhaps the most obvious feature
是白色部分，称为巩膜，虹膜。现在巩膜是纤维组织，
is the white part, which is called the sclera, and the iris. Now the sclera is fibrous tissue,
这是眼睛结构和某些动物巩膜的重要组成部分
which is an important part of the structure of the eye and some kinds of animals the sclera
实际上它里面有骨质成分，在这个化石中你可以看到一个骨头环，
actually has bony components in it and in this fossil here you can see a ring of bone,
这实际上是该动物眼睛巩膜的一部分。
which is actually part of the sclera of that animal’s eye.
如果我们在这里看右眼的横截面，我们可以看到巩膜
If we look at the cross section of the eye on the right here, we can see that the sclera
它是围绕眼球本身的膜的一部分。我们可以看到虹膜和
which is part of the membrane that surrounds the eyeball itself. We can see the iris and
瞳孔调节进入眼睛的光线。我们可以看到镜头，这是
the pupil which regulates the light going into the eye. We can see the lens, which is
透明的结晶蛋白质结构，将光线聚焦在视网膜上
a transparent, crystalline protein structure which focuses the light onto the retina on
眼睛后面。眼睛里面充满了公平
the back of the eye. The inside of the eye is filled with a fairly
透明的液体，在眼睛的后部，我们有一个被称为的表面
transparent fluid, and at the back of the eye we have a surface which is called the
视网膜，一个包含光感受器的曲面，即光敏感的
retina, a curved surface which contains the photoreceptors, that is, the light sensitive
眼睛的一部分。然后通过这个大神经束-视神经-连接到大脑。
part of the eye. And that is then connected by this big nerve bundle—the optic nerve—to the brain.
事实上，我们实际上可以将眼睛视为大脑的一部分。它
In fact, we can actually think of the eye as being a part of the brain. It
通过显着的神经束连接，然后眼睛基本上是感觉
is connected by a significant nerve bundle, and then the eye is essentially a sensory
大脑的一部分位于我们的头脑中。
part of the brain located in the front of our heads.
现在让我们在眼睛的视网膜上更详细地看一下。因此，如果我们采取横断面，我们会移动
Let’s now look in more detail at the retina of the eye. So if we take a transect, we move
从眼睛内侧到眼睛外侧，我们经过的箭头方向
from inside the eye to outside of the eye along the direction of that arrow we pass
通过许多层细胞和血管等等。现在这一切都在
through a number of layers of cells and blood vessels and whatever. Now this is all on a
相当小的规模;这种总结构厚约500微米。
pretty small scale; this total structure is about 500 microns thick.
光敏电池位于该结构的底部。所以他们不在
The light sensitive cells are at the bottom of this structure. So they are not on the
在视网膜表面，它们实际上在视网膜表面下方约500微米处。
surface of the retina, they are actually about 500 microns below the surface of the retina.
因此，光必须穿过-通过这些细胞和血管扩散
So the light has to pass through—diffuse through—these cells and blood vessels before
它到达光敏细胞。现在你可能听过有人说话了
it gets to the light sensitive cells. Now you’ve probably heard people talking
关于杆和锥体。杆细胞和锥细胞是光敏元件。
about rods and cones. The rods cells and the cone cells are the light sensitive elements.
它们是我们眼中的光感受器。杆细胞是这些意大利面形状的结构。
They are the photoreceptors in our eye. The rod cells are these spaghetti shaped structures.
他们有点瘦。而且它们对低光照水平很敏感。所以我们使用杆细胞
They are kind of thin. And they are sensitive to low light levels. So we use the rod cells
当我们在光线很弱的环境中工作时。锥形细胞是这些奇怪的，凹凸不平的形状
when we are working in a very low light environment. The cone cells are these strange, stumpy shaped
细胞;它们有点圆锥形，有点蹲，不像杆那么高。还有这些
cells; they are a little bit conical, kind of squat, not as tall as the rods. And these
细胞对颜色敏感。并且有三种不同类型的锥体细胞：那里
cells are sensitive to colour. And there are three different types of cones cells: there
有些是对红光敏感的，有些是对绿光敏感而有些是敏感的
are some that are sensitive to red light, some sensitive to green light and some sensitive
蓝灯。但他们共同的特点是它们有点像圆锥形。
to blue light. But the characteristic they all share is that they are this somewhat conical shape.
我们可以考虑眼睛的另一种方式是
Another way we can consider the eye is to
看看光纤连接视网膜的位置，并在视网膜上形成一个区域
look at where the optic fibre joins the retina and that creates an area on the retina which
被称为光盘，其中实际上没有光敏细胞。所以有一部分
is called the optic disk where there are actually no light sensitive cells. So there is a part
对视网膜无反应的视网膜还有视网膜的另一部分
of the retina that does not respond to light. And there is another part of the retina where
我们有一个巨大的光敏细胞集中，这个区域被称为
we have an enormous concentration of light sensitive cells and that area is called the
小窝。中央凹与视神经分开一段距离。
fovea. The fovea and the optic nerve are separated by some distance.
所以在这张图中，我们将看到的是感光细胞的密度，
So in this graph here what we are going to see is the density of photoreceptor cells,
并且在该区域中每平方毫米的锥形细胞数量存在巨大的峰值
and there is a huge peak in the number of cone cells per square millimetre in this area
我们称之为中央凹。因此，我们在这一小部分区域内拥有精致的分辨率。其余的部分
we call the fovea. So we have exquisite resolution in this one small area of our eye. The rest
在眼睛方面，我们的分辨率要低得多，不知不觉中我们的眼睛不断移动，
of the eye, we have much less resolution and unconsciously our eye is continually moving,
聚焦在场景的不同部分，将中央凹指向这些不同的部分。
focusing, on different parts of the scene, directing the fovea to these different parts.
因此，我们通过指导高分辨率中央凹来建立高分辨率的图像
So we build up a high resolution of the image by directing the high resolution fovea all
我们正在看的场景。现在使用棒状细胞它们有很大不同
over the scene we are looking at. Now with the rod cells they have a quite different
空间密度模式。中央凹区域的杆状细胞很少，但有
spatial density pattern. There are very few rod cells in the fovea area, but there’s
我们称之为周边视觉的更多杆细胞;远离我们眼睛的方向
many more rod cells in what we call our peripheral vision; away from the direction that our eye
指着。这在夜间非常有用，这些细胞也有些运动敏感。
is pointing. This is very useful at night and these cells are also somewhat motion sensitive.
它们使我们能够看到从我们眼角移动的东西。
They are what give us the ability to see something moving out of the corner of our eye.
那么真正有趣的是视神经进入视网膜的这项业务
So what is really interesting then is this business of the optic nerve entering the retina
并创造我们称之为盲点的东西。现在我们可以真正发现我们的盲点
and creating what we call the blind spot. Now we can actually detect our blind spot
使用模式，像这样的东西。所以你做的就是闭上你的右眼并盯着看
using a pattern, something like this. So what you do is close your right eye and stare at
加号。然后绝对地将你的头朝向和远离屏幕移动
the plus sign. And then move your head toward and away from the screen making absolutely
确保你用左眼看着加号。当你移动你的头
sure that you are looking with your left eye at the plus sign. As you move your head in
然后，这里的圆圈会在某个点落到视网膜上的视盘上
and out, the circle here will at some point fall onto the optic disk on your retina and
令人惊讶的是，它会从视野中消失。所以你可以有一些
it will, quite surprisingly, it will just disappear from view. So you can have some
通过这样的测试，您可以在线找到其他人。玩一玩，看看你能不能找到
fun with a test like this, you can find others online. Have a play and see if you can find
你的盲点。令人惊讶的是，在日常生活中我们没有注意到我们
your blind spot. It is quite surprising that in everyday life we don’t notice that we
有一个盲点。我们遇到了一些麻烦，我们实际上可以发现它就在那里。
have got a blind spot. We go to a bit of trouble, we can actually detect that it is there.
现在，如果我们看一下大脑的水平横截面。我们可以看到
Now if we look at, for instance, our horizontal cross section of the brain. We can see the
眼睛位于头部前方，视神经束带有视觉信息
eyes located at the front of the head and the optic nerve bundles carry the visual information
通过大脑到大脑的后部，我们拥有视觉皮层。和
through the brain to the back part of the brain, where we have our visual cortex. And
这就是我们所有真正令人兴奋的视觉处理正在进行的地方。那就是
that is where we have all the really exciting visual processing going on. That is where
我们大脑的一部分负责识别人和物体以及运动等。但
part of our brain is responsible for recognising people and objects and motion and so on. But
人脑是一个非常复杂的结构。它的重量约为1.5公斤
the human brain is a very complex structure. It weighs something like 1.5 kilograms and
那里约有1011个神经元。这是一个非常多的计算和内存功能。
is about 1011 neurons in there. So an awful lot of computation and memory capability.
其中近三分之一用于处理视觉信息。
Nearly a third of that is devoted to processing visual information.
早些时候我们使用的论点是眼睛已经被进化发明了很多次
Earlier we used the argument that the eye has been invented so many times by evolution
它必须是一种非常有效的动物传感器。但这种感觉是有代价的
that it must be a very effective sensor for animals. But there is a cost for the sense
在人类的情况下，其中一个成本是我们的三分之一
of vision, and in the case of human beings one of those costs is that a third of our
大脑致力于处理这种视觉信息。所以是的，这是非常有效的
brain is devoted to processing this visual information. So yes, it is a very effective
传感器，作为一个有机体，我们为运行该传感器付出了相当大的代价。
sensor that as an organism we pay quite a cost in order to run that sensor.
额外的费用与眼睛本身有关。
Additional costs are associated with the eyes themselves.
它们是非常精致的结构，所以我们进化出保护眼睛的机制。
They are very delicate structures, so we evolved mechanisms to protect the eye.
例如，我们的眼睑和睫毛，用泪管清洁眼睛的机制等等，
For instance, our eyelids and eyelashes, mechanisms to clean the eyes with tear ducts and so on,
并且一些非常高性能的肌肉也会使眼睛在头部内移动。
and the eyes are also moved within the head by some very high performance muscles.
因此，有很多辅助机制参与维持视觉。
So there is a lot of auxiliary machinery involved in maintaining the sense of vision.